<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>unsolicited remarks</title>
      <link>https://unsolicitedremarks.com</link>
      <description></description>
      <generator>Zola</generator>
      <language>en</language>
      <atom:link href="https://unsolicitedremarks.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <item>
          <title>Twister!</title>
          <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://unsolicitedremarks.com/poetry/twister/</link>
          <guid>https://unsolicitedremarks.com/poetry/twister/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://unsolicitedremarks.com/poetry/twister/">&lt;p&gt;Clouds having given way to sunshine on this June afternoon,
a family sits silently together on the sunporch, senses
dulled by their recent loss, though noticing the humidity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their dad
     granddad
          husband
               lays in the next room, finally.
His spirit, evaporating in the heat, adds only more moisture to an
environment ripe for rage, catalyzed by the dissonant mourning
for this dearly departed thorn bush—untamed, unpruned, vengeful.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fueled by hot moisture, instability, a life spent at odds with itself,
the spirit slowly growing fifty thousand feet into the stratosphere,
no longer bound by the limitations of his physical body,
a cathartic feedback loop of air molecules—&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;rising
    falling
        rage
            calm reaching its fever pitch in some
proximal field, victim of happenstance, the chaotic wind leaving
behind crops blown over and carved into a meandering stream,
one final path of destruction left in his wake, dissipating at last—
tired, docile, now a suitable offering for the afterlife.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meteorologist in some distant forecast office not having
even noticed this short-lived twister in the middle of Nowhere.
They&#x27;ll keep watching the sweep on their monitors, drinking their
coffee, thinking about what to eat tonight for dinner.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though we out here are left to tidy up this mess, the winds
calm and air cool, as we wait to bear the brunt
of the next one to die without having
fully satisfied the grudge they
held against themself
all these
years.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Emotional Default</title>
          <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://unsolicitedremarks.com/essays/emotional-default/</link>
          <guid>https://unsolicitedremarks.com/essays/emotional-default/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://unsolicitedremarks.com/essays/emotional-default/">&lt;p&gt;This week is the essentially the same as any other week, except that it marks the 3rd year since my dad died.  Similar to how some people treat their birthday weeks, I want to spend this one engaged in a quiet version of self-pity and loathing—engrossed in my own romanticized thinking about how one should react to or process the turning of the years marking a parent&#x27;s death.  It doesn&#x27;t help anyone, but damn does it &lt;em&gt;feel good now&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;I&#x27;m going to phone it in this week,&quot;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; I think to myself as I settle into my desk at work on Monday morning.  &lt;em&gt;&quot;None of the other people here have to deal with this like I do.&quot;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;  It seems to me that I&#x27;m entitled to a form of do-nothing job this week, not have to work much if at all, instead engaging in low-level pointless tasks masquerading as work so my colleagues don&#x27;t suspect anything.  I&#x27;ll need to keep my brain lightly tasked, of course, lest my default mode network be allowed to wander into the parts of my thinking where I do have some agency in my life and change is not an insurmountable obstacle and for whatever fucking reason the walls are plastered in inspirational posters like &lt;em&gt;yesterday is history tomorrow is a mystery today is a gift that&#x27;s why they call it the present&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My dad&#x27;s death was tragic in the sense that he went from &quot;decently well&quot; to dead in a matter of months and that it was not without his suffering, but it was not, ultimately, tragic.  I think certain Buddhists would probably argue that no death is &lt;em&gt;tragic&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, that saying any death is a &lt;em&gt;tragedy&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; makes a certain Western value judgement about the finality of death and implicitly regards life on a sort of &quot;value&quot; spectrum. Though, &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;sccei.fsi.stanford.edu&#x2F;china-briefs&#x2F;assessing-chinas-national-model-social-credit-system&quot;&gt;who is&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;apnews.com&#x2F;article&#x2F;chinese-surveillance-silicon-valley-uyghurs-tech-xinjiang-a80904158b771a14d5a734947f28d71b&quot;&gt;to say&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is &lt;em&gt;the Year of our Lord Two Thousand Twenty Five&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; and my dad died in 2022.  He was 56, a few months shy of a birthday, and I was almost 4 months into my 28th year.  My daughter dropped a sucker on the floor today.  This, to her, was a tragedy.  She has a relatively brief history to draw upon.  It&#x27;s probably most appropriate, lexically, for me to say instead something like, &quot;My father&#x27;s death was the most impactful event in my life to date.&quot;  Since then, my daughter was born, the life soup of three years has simmered, which is to say the timeline of my life continues to unfold—events continue to occur, the aggregate result of which diminishes the impact of happenings in my life on and throughout the weeks following October 30, 2022.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Healing is not simply a function of time dilution.  Me forgetting doesn&#x27;t mean I&#x27;m cured.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting aside my mixed experiences with my father&#x27;s tender moments and alcohol fueled episodes of rage, it would be impossible for me to fully flesh-out the pros and cons list of &quot;dad&#x27;s dead&quot; in a way that acknowledges the present moment while also accurately measuring future impact.  For just about every &quot;negative&quot; aspect of my father being dead I can think of a &quot;positive&quot; one; or, perhaps I&#x27;m still a bit too close to see the issue clear-eyed.  &quot;Jesus Christ,&quot; you may exclaim upon reading the idea of a pros and cons list for a close family member dying.  I can agree, it seems absurd—though any remotely critical assessment of death and dying practices in the United States should result in a similar conclusion.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A physician colleague of mine once broke the news to me that another colleague of ours had unexpectedly died.  She said exactly that, &quot;so-and-so &lt;strong&gt;is dead&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&quot;  The news was hard to hear, but the way she phrased it was such a breath of fresh air—real, raw, unfiltered—and so unlike my prior close experiences with death that my emotional path forward was made that much clearer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without such a clarity of vision in this circumstance, I&#x27;m left wondering what should be the &quot;right&quot; way for me to mark this annual passage of time.  The proximity of &lt;em&gt;the event&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; to &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Samhain#Spirits_and_souls&quot;&gt;Samhain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; seems like a natural fit but I think some fundamental underpinnings of the holiday are, essentially, bullshit—so that&#x27;s off the table.  A weeklong decent into self-pity seems unfitting of an emotionally well-developed adult.  I would like to get close to a place where I&#x27;m able to acknowledge the continuation of his life in mine, annually disavow the parts of his life that were harmful, all while tangibly getting something out of the experience like a day off work or a nice coffee.  This year I&#x27;ll probably just do the tangible part and start to lay the foundation for work on the intangible stuff—saving the real work for next year.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all, I decided on Monday: this week I&#x27;m &lt;a rel=&quot;noopener nofollow noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.vocabulary.com&#x2F;articles&#x2F;wordroutes&#x2F;mailbag-friday-phoning-it-in&#x2F;&quot;&gt;phoning it in&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Blinking</title>
          <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://unsolicitedremarks.com/poetry/blinking/</link>
          <guid>https://unsolicitedremarks.com/poetry/blinking/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://unsolicitedremarks.com/poetry/blinking/">&lt;p&gt;Children, as they sleep, process new information into memories.
Parents, while their children sleep, contemplate the future—&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tonight, though, I am at war with myself, examining my life&#x27;s
frustrating contours, revealing my weaknesses and faults—&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What weapon can arrest the march of the doldrums,
our steady processional toward the solitude of death?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What must I do to transcend the weight of living,
to commune with God while still here—&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To signal to the fireflies, my lacking light,
I understand.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Made in the USA</title>
          <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://unsolicitedremarks.com/poetry/made-in-the-usa/</link>
          <guid>https://unsolicitedremarks.com/poetry/made-in-the-usa/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://unsolicitedremarks.com/poetry/made-in-the-usa/">&lt;p&gt;I am the flag of the country
chosen for her beacon—holding
hope, prosperity, stability like
water in between open fingers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am the social worker
called in on her day off to
respond—as a bystander
might at a burning home—
how, exactly?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am the shop owner switching
&quot;abrir&quot; to &quot;cerrado&quot; at noon,
worried about a day of
sales lost and a dream torn
apart in a day.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am the officer upholding the
Rule of Law that grinds
against the Law of God in the way
an ulcer is only a beginning.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am the spouse abruptly set adrift,
unmoored, ignored, whose cries
for help at night willfully unheard
echo through the canyon formed
between intent and purpose—&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am the child whose parent
won&#x27;t be home tonight—
whose chance at a carefree childhood
was destroyed for politicking, profit, greed—
whose siblings too early look to for
comfort, assurance—absent my own.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am the child
I am the spouse
I am the officer
I am the social worker
I am the flag&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;whose stripes in summer heat languish,
whose winds of justice stagnate,
whose symbolism willingly fouled.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are the immigrant,
undocumented,
unvalued,
inhuman—except—&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;fearfully and wonderfully made.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Bodhisattva</title>
          <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://unsolicitedremarks.com/poetry/bodhisattva/</link>
          <guid>https://unsolicitedremarks.com/poetry/bodhisattva/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://unsolicitedremarks.com/poetry/bodhisattva/">&lt;p&gt;Where do we learn
the delicate art
of thinking our life
is more precious
than our neighbor’s?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it in the pews
of a church, holy rollers
preaching that our dogma
confers upon us some
unquestionable superiority?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could it be our own
parents, caring for us
like a precious gem
from the day we were
suddenly forced into consciousness?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it is some deep
dark thing within us,
Freud’s Id, the constant
thumping drumbeat of
self-obsessed desire.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I cause this
unwelcome part of me
to come suddenly,
thoroughly, upon a
beautiful, mournless death?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where may I address it—
packaged tightly in paper,
tied up using too much twine—
to be certain it will be
forever lost along the way?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can I be entirely sure
that the thought will
never cross my mind again,
that my life carries
greater eternal weight&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;than that of a friend,
a stranger,
a bird,
water,
air?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Frank Lloyd Wright</title>
          <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://unsolicitedremarks.com/poetry/frank-lloyd-wright/</link>
          <guid>https://unsolicitedremarks.com/poetry/frank-lloyd-wright/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://unsolicitedremarks.com/poetry/frank-lloyd-wright/">&lt;p&gt;designed buildings
with elements that
evoked a sense of
anticipation in
moving from
room to room—
corridors with low
ceilings and slender
passageways
opening into&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;large, airy spaces with enormous features and high ceilings,
to him evoking thusly a sense of freedom and unbound wonder—
a principle he would term “compression and release.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strange, then,
despite having
died in ‘fifty-nine,
his hand apparently
still busy drafting
the contours of
this life, dark
years opening into
grander eras,
sixty years later.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps this poem, rising in smoke and ash, will cause him to imagine
a new design, one that rejects the catastrophes—compression—
and emphatically embraces God’s conclusion—release.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>This Number is No Longer in Service</title>
          <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://unsolicitedremarks.com/poetry/this-number-is-no-longer-in-service/</link>
          <guid>https://unsolicitedremarks.com/poetry/this-number-is-no-longer-in-service/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://unsolicitedremarks.com/poetry/this-number-is-no-longer-in-service/">&lt;p&gt;I had wondered why you weren&#x27;t at my daughter&#x27;s baby shower
or how come you didn&#x27;t attend my birthday dinner—&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come to think of it, it seems we missed celebrating
your own birthday this year.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your absence seemed conspicuous, though unsurprising,
as we both know your proclivity to skip these sorts of engagements.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then I remembered where I saw you last,
and it suddenly all made sense—&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My offense waned, though slowly, as
I realized I&#x27;d have to forgive your absence
at many celebrations to come.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Third Verse to Coda</title>
          <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://unsolicitedremarks.com/poetry/third-verse-to-coda/</link>
          <guid>https://unsolicitedremarks.com/poetry/third-verse-to-coda/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://unsolicitedremarks.com/poetry/third-verse-to-coda/">&lt;p&gt;Staring into the vast empty
blue of the sky, I was suddenly
arrested by the overwhelming
heaviness of being alive.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My body began to dissolve into
its elements, breath to vapor,
body to earth, spirit to sky, my
awareness slowly weightless.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consciousness formed into cloud,
shifting and billowing and dancing
a great choreographed ballet as
it was perfectly meant to be.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Telling the story of unspeakable beauty,
of horrifying tragedy, grief, and sorrow.
Of struggle, of joy, of delight—
past, present, future.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scenes carefully orchestrated,
dancers with routines memorized,
water vapor perfectly portraying birth,
death, in their due time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why should these be happening now,
known to my body but not my
consciousness, the parts of my life
that must happen, no matter what?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine then, the feeling of my 
becoming aware—once again—
of myself, sky without a cloud,
but the remains of overwhelming grief.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should I twitch my fingers,
move my feet, breathe?
Should I feel the sun on my face,
the grass beneath my back, air?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I’ll give thanks for a moment,
to whomever or whatever will listen,
for my being alive, I think.
Or, perhaps, the compassion of a new day.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Drought</title>
          <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://unsolicitedremarks.com/poetry/drought/</link>
          <guid>https://unsolicitedremarks.com/poetry/drought/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://unsolicitedremarks.com/poetry/drought/">&lt;p&gt;Grass dry as dust, like dull sewing
needles beneath my bare feet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trees desperately seeking for water,
leaves wilting, their telltale call of distress.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunlight close to my skin, burning
white hot as embers in a camp fire.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bluejay shifts from her perch, blue body
stark against these drab browns and dull reds.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could she know something I don’t, maybe
some respite place not too far from here?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now I’ll make do with resting here in the
stale shade under this great thirsty maple.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I’ll communion with the bluejay,
mutually graced with the pains of life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally she would flit between branches
and trees, carrying about her day’s work.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today she rests with all the other birds,
well understanding that now is not the time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She knows this heat is only temporary,
September rain soon opening into fall.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How quickly each of us will forget this
dreadfulness in the cool of October!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About this time a year from now, perhaps
this very bluejay will remember me, and I her,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;our shared experience steeling us against
the unrelenting tide of seasons.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together we will once again prevail—I having 
learned, she having already known—the&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cyclical nature of these things, the natural
sinusoidal curves of life, highs and lows.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, more likely, I will forget all but how it felt,
she forgetting all but what what to do.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
